Jalerson Lima, MSc

Senior Ruby on Rails Developer

Phone: 1 (647) 846-3159 GitHub: http://www.github.com/jalerson

E-mail: jalerson@gmail.com **Website:** http://jalerson.me

LinkedIn: http://www.linkedin.com/in/jalerson

Summary

Senior Ruby on Rails Developer and Project Leader at the Laboratory of Technology Innovations in Healthcare. Professor of Software Development and Engineering at the Federal Institute of Education at Rio Grande do Norte. Master in Systems and Computing at the Federal University of Rio Grande do Norte.

Experience and Skills

- 7 years' experience in Ruby on Rails framework;
- 10+ years of software development experience using a variety of front and back-end technologies, platforms and tools (Ruby on Rails, PHP, Java, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, JQuery, JavaScript);
- Experience on developing high-performance web applications using agile methodologies;
- Strong background in computer science and software engineering;
- Solid experience working collaboratively using Git, GitHub, GitLab and BitBucket;
- Experience using SQL and relational databases, such as MySQL and PostgreSQL;
- Passionate for continuous learning and improvement.

Work Experience

Laboratory of Technology Innovations in Healthcare – Natal, Brazil

Senior Ruby on Rails Developer and Project Leader 2012 – Present

I'm the main web developer and leader of the Telepediatrics project. Telepediatrics is a web-based system, developed in Ruby on Rails, to support non-specialist doctors in pediatric appointments, allowing them to discuss cases with remote medical specialists. In these days, Telepediatrics is really big and complex project, which handles sensitive and law-protected data, supporting doctors by using complex algorithms to perform statistical analysis and calculations, such as insulin therapy, Z-Score and percentiles of anthropometry measures, as well as automatic detecting issues on neurodevelopment, vaccination and so on. Currently, I'm also coordinating the team that is developing the Telepediatrics mobile application in Android, iOS and Windows Phone, as well as building an API to integrate our system to our mobile app.

I also had the opportunity to start, from scratch, the Dengue National Observatory, which is a web-based system, built in Ruby on Rails, to support public healthcare agents to track cases and proliferation spots of the *Aedes Aegypt* mosquito. System in action: http://youtu.be/kWvhaHXv-70.

During two months, I also coordinated the SISCOAPES project, which is a web-based system built in Django, to support the federal government in monitoring the operation of medical residents in healthcare centers. All the system features were remotely negotiated with public healthcare specialists from the Brazilian Ministry of Health.

Sync Systems - Natal, Brazil

Senior Ruby on Rails Developer 2009 – 2010

Senior Ruby on Rails developer of the internal management system of the Telepesquisa Company, built in Ruby on Rails. Project built by me from scratch: negotiating and collecting functional requirements at client's site. The Telepesquisa management system had to import millions of records of other partner companies. I also was the main developer of the Bluesync, which is a Bluetooth marketing software developed in Java.

Symetrix Corp. - Colorado Springs, USA

Remote Systems Analyst Consultant 2008 – 2009

Remote Systems Analyst Consultant of the Eye of the Eagle project, which was a system to prevent tax evasion of the Rio de Janeiro government. I worked in Java, C and C# components, handling with smart cards and RFID (Radio-frequency Identification). In this position, I had my first experience negotiating features and deadlines with the clients in English.

Real Security - Natal, Brazil

Developer and Software Architect 2007

I worked as a software developer and architect to develop an Electronic Security Monitoring System used by the company. The system, built in Java, had to manage all the security signals sent by devices located in the clients houses.

Ministry of Education – Brasília, Brazil

Web Developer 2007

I worked as web developer to build the Knowledge Connections Portal to the Secretary of Continuing Education, Literacy, Diversity and Inclusion of the Ministry of Education. The portal, developed in Mentawai (Brazilian MVC Java Framework), it was nationally used to register and monitor projects conducted by federal universities.

Brazilian Agency for the Aquaculture Development – Natal, Brazil

Web Developer 2006

Web developer of the RECARCINE Portal, built in PHP, which was a portal for the Brazilian Agency for the Aquaculture Development.

Education

Master of Science in Systems and Computing

Federal University of Rio Grande do Norte – Natal, Brazil 2012 – 2014

Specialist in Systems Engineering

Open Superior School of Brazil – Vila Velha, Brazil 2008 – 2010

Bachelor of Science in Software Development

Federal Institute of Education 2004 – 2007